(拍手)
♪♪｢夕方６時は ｸﾞﾀﾞｸﾞﾀﾞ｣
♪♪｢ちょっと
ｼｬｷｯとしろ ｼｬｷｯと！｣
いったん ＣＭです！
♪♪｢やっぱり
どうでもよきかな｣
♪♪｢ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄ Ｘ｣
♪♪｢ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄ｣
♪♪｢笑ってよきかな
ｸﾞｽﾞｸﾞｽﾞｽﾊﾟｰｷﾝ ｲｴｲ｣
♪♪｢ｸﾞﾗｻﾝの奥は 写輪眼｣
♪♪｢ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄ｣
♪♪｢何年やっても お値段据え置き｣
♪♪(多毛)｢そんなの
ｵﾚも同じだよ お前！ えっ!?｣
♪♪｢臨兵闘者皆陣列在前｣
♪♪(よきかな中年隊)
｢Give me money！ 予算を上げて｣
♪♪(よきかな中年隊)｢あぁ～
さすがに４週も歌うと飽きたわ｣
♪♪｢夕方６時は ｸﾞｽﾞｸﾞｽﾞ｣
明日も どうでもよきかな｣
♪♪｢そう 今どき４対３なんて
うちぐらい｣
♪♪～
♪♪(みんな)
｢ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄ ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄ ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄ！｣
Feeling all beat by 6 PM.
[The Tamo-san Hour Smile! Is that Good? Final Episode!]
いったん ＣＭです！
Everything's still all good.
(みんな)えぇ～！
Getting all bitchy by 6 PM.
♪♪～
Tomorrow will be all good.
Yeah, after four weeks, we're starting to get tired of this.
I feel the same way, y'know?
Get your act together, damn it!
Yosan wo agete.
Give me money!
Yes!
We're the only ones using 4:3 in this day and age.
After all these years, the costs haven't changed!
Rin, pyou, tou, sha, kai, jin, retsu, zai, zen.
[Note: Refers to the Nine Symbolic Cuts/Syllables often used in Buddhism  meditation.]
Sharingan hiding behind my sunglasses.
[Note: Parody of Tamori and Sharingan from Naruto.]
♪♪～
Laugh away! Bitchin' sparking! Yay!
こんばんは｡
Project X.
(みんな)こんばんは！
Project.
今日で最終回ですね｡
(みんな)そうですね！
Project X.
いったん ＣＭです！
Project.
(みんな)えぇ～！
Project, project.
♪♪～
Project.
We'll cut to a commercial for now.
["Shocked by the Phone"]
What?!
Good evening.
Good evening!
Today's the last episode.
Sure is!
We'll cut to a commercial for now.
What?!
We've had a lot of commercial breaks today.
Sure have!
Shall I call in a guest now?
Sure thing!
Then we'll cut to a commercial first...
What? We're out of commercials?
♪♪～
今日は ＣＭ多いね｡
I see...
Then we'll cut to GinTama for now.
(みんな)そうですね！
そろそろ ｹﾞｽﾄ呼んじゃう？
じゃあ その前に
いったん ＣＭ… ん？
えっ うん… もうＣＭない？
あっ そう…｡
じゃあ いったん 『銀魂』です｡
♪♪～
I'm definitely going to take it!
《新八:つかみとるんだ！
勝利を… みんなで勝利を！》
Victory! Victory for all of us!
(銀時)あとは ｵﾚたちに任せな！
We'll handle the rest.
あっ!? 銀さん！ たかち…｡
Gin-san!
Taka-chin!
えっ… 誰それ？
Who is that?
[ﾏｲｸ]来ました！ 寺門通公式ﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞ
決定！ 戦場のﾋﾟｱﾆｽﾄ予選１位は➡
Here we are!
First place in the prelims for the pianist battle to decide Tsu Terakado's official fan club is
ﾁｰﾑ 通選組 ﾄｯｼｰ氏！
team Tsusengumi's Toshi!
他ﾁｰﾑと手を組みﾗｲﾊﾞﾙを蹴落とし
みごとﾄｯﾌﾟで ｺﾞｰﾙのﾃｰﾌﾟを切った！
After joining forces with the other teams to beat his rivals, he has now crossed the line!
A fine job of using wits to win the marathon prelim, believed to be a test of stamina!
体力勝負と思われた
予選ﾏﾗｿﾝ対決を➡
知力を駆使することで
みごと制しました！
Well done. Majumbo lottery.
(お通)お疲れｻﾏｰｼﾞｬﾝﾎﾞ宝くじ！
(土方)ありがとうございます大山｡
Thank you very much. Huge mountain.
Excuse me! Could you look this way?
すみませ～ん！
こちらに表情くださ～い！
And especially impressive was the power displayed in commanding the other teams!
[ﾏｲｸ]何よりも特筆すべきは
敵ﾁｰﾑを丸め込み➡
従わせてしまった その支配力！
恐るべき通選組！
The Tsusengumi is a fearsome force!
果たして このﾁｰﾑに勝てるﾁｰﾑが
存在するのでしょうか!?
Is there a team capable of defeating them?!
《ﾌﾝ！ もとより
ｵﾚの手駒だったということに➡
They still haven't realized that these people were my pawns to begin with?
まだ気づいてねえのか…》
[ﾏｲｸ]現在 彼らに続くﾁｰﾑが
まったく見当たりません！
There are no other teams in sight!
通選組 ﾀﾞﾝﾄﾂ１位です！
The Tsusengumi has an overwhelming lead!
[ﾏｲｸ]いや～ それにしても
まったく見えないというのは➡
But isn't it kind of odd that there isn't anybody else coming?
ちょっとおかしな気もしますねぇ｡
Was there an accident back there somewhere?
[ﾏｲｸ]後ろで事故でも
あったのでしょうか？
《ﾔﾂらの足止めに
手こずっているのか？
You're having trouble holding them back?
まあいい｡ ﾔﾂらがあの ぶ厚い肉の
壁を抜けられるわけがない》
It doesn't matter.
It isn't possible for them to break through that human wall.
あっ 今 情報が入りました！
We have a report!
They're giving up!
棄権！ なんと
ｺﾞｰﾙにたどり着く前に➡
We have information that a large number of teams are giving up before reaching the goal!
大多数のﾁｰﾑが次々と
棄権していっているとの情報が｡
A bridge has been knocked out at the seven kilometer mark!
７ｷﾛ地点 橋崩落！
A train has derailed at a crossing at the eight kilometer mark!
８ｷﾛ地点
踏み切りで貨物列車脱線！
A large quantity of dog shit has appeared at the nine kilometer mark!
９ｷﾛ地点 犬のﾌﾝ大量発生！
What is going on here?!
[ﾏｲｸ]これは いったい
何が起こっているのでしょうか？
[ﾏｲｸ]まるで天災に
見舞われたかのように➡
It's as if the heavens have decided to rain natural disaster after disaster to impede the otakus!
次々にｺｰｽ上で異変が起き
ｵﾀｸたちを足止めしている！
[ﾏｲｸ]９ｷﾛ以降 ｺｰｽを走るのは
なんとたったの１ﾁｰﾑ！
Only one team is past the nine kilometer mark!
[ﾏｲｸ]まさかその１ﾁｰﾑがこの事態を
引き起こしているのか？
Could that team have caused this?!
Is that humanly possible?!
[ﾏｲｸ]そんなことが
人間に可能なのか？
《ま まさかﾔﾂらが？
いや そんなことが》
D-Don't tell me they...
No... That's not...
Ah! Please take a look!
[ﾏｲｸ]あ～ 見てください！
風吹きすさぶ無人の野を➡
We have a team running through the empty streets!
駆けてくるﾁｰﾑの姿が！
[ﾏｲｸ]あれは あのﾊｯﾋﾟは
寺門通親衛隊の…｡
It's...!
That coat is...!
The Tsu Terakado Fan Club's...!
(土方)誰だ？
Who the hell is that?!
Okay!
ｵｯｹｰ！
(ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ)ｲｴｽ！
Yes!
Okay, we've made it to the finals. Yay.
よっしゃ 本選勝ち残り！ ｲｴｰｲ！
[ﾏｲｸ]寺門通親衛隊 ﾋﾞﾘｹﾂから大逆転！
The Tsu Terakado Fan Club has made an amazing comeback!
[ﾏｲｸ]なんと ２位でｺﾞｰﾙ！
They've finished in second!
Hold it right there!
ちょっと待て！ 誰だ それ！
どこから連れてきたんだ！
Who the hell is that?!
Where did you get him?!
何で 知らねえﾔﾂが
ｽﾛｰﾓｰｼｮﾝでｺﾞｰﾙﾃｰﾌﾟ切ってんだ！
Why is a total stranger crossing the finish line in slow motion?!
こんなﾔﾂ ﾃﾒｴらのﾁｰﾑに
いなかっただろうが！
This guy wasn't on your team!
Yeah, enough of that already.
ああ いい いい｡
もう そういうのは➡
We already saw that reaction enough times last week.
そういうﾘｱｸｼｮﾝは
先週 十分見たから｡
(土方)何だその態度は？
替え玉仕込んどいて➡
What's with the attitude?!
How can you be so shameless when you used an illegal sub?!
どんだけふてぶてしい
態度取ってんだ！
替え玉？ おい 証拠もねえのに
妙な言いがかりはよせ｡
Illegal sub?
Hey, don't make baseless claims when you have no evidence.
Evidence? That guy right there is the evidence!
証拠って
まるまるｺｲﾂが証拠だろうが！
Caught red-handed, damn it!
現行犯逮捕だろうが！
土方君 ﾏﾗｿﾝてのは
人生と同じなんだよ｡
Hijikata-kun, a marathon is like life.
艱難辛苦をのり越えてな➡
After making it through trials and tribulations,
ｺﾞｰﾙﾃｰﾌﾟを切る頃には すっかり
成長して まるで別人のように…｡
you've matured so much that by the time
you cross the finish line you're practically a different person...
別人だろうが！
まごうことなき別人だろうが！
He's a different person!
He's obviously a different person!
わからねえﾔﾂだな｡
You just don't get it.
あっ
ちょうどいいところに ご到着だ｡
Ah, he's come at a perfect time.
ほら 見てみろ｡
お前らのﾁｰﾑﾒｲﾄの姿を｡
There, have a look at your teammate.
Yamazaki-kun has also matured and completely changed.
山崎君も成長して
すっかり変わって｡
His hairdo's changed!
(土方)
髪型変わってんじゃねえか！
Why would his hairdo change during a marathon?!
何で ﾏﾗｿﾝで髪型が変わるんだよ！
Why would a hairdo mature during a marathon?!
何でﾏﾗｿﾝで
髪型が成長するんだよ！
成長っていうか
どう見ても劣化してるし！
And wait, this would be the opposite of maturing!
[ﾏｲｸ]おっと
親衛隊に続き 通選組のﾒﾝﾊﾞｰも➡
Oh! And after the arrival of the Tsu Terakado Fan Club,
we have a member of the Tsusengumi who's practically a different person!
まるで別人のように
変わってしまったようです！
(山崎)うっ… こんな派手な頭で➡
How am I supposed to carry out my job as inspector with this wild hairdo?
これからどうやって監察の
仕事を続けていけばいいんだ｡
山崎 お前まさかｺｲﾂらに…｡
Yamazaki, don't tell me those guys...
すみません｡
ﾍﾏやらかしちまいました｡
I'm sorry. I goofed up.
でも土方さん
ここは流してください｡
But Hijikata-san, please just let it go.
ここは ﾔﾂらを
見逃してやってください｡
Just overlook it.
ｵﾚたち もっと
ﾔﾊﾞｲ不正ﾔﾂらに握られています｡
They're holding a much bigger offense over our heads.
(沖田)あっ ここでいいです｡
Ah, this is the place.
大丈夫 大丈夫 ﾊﾞﾚやしやせんよ｡
Don't worry. Don't worry.
I won't get caught.
ああ 領収書もお願いします｡
土方十四郎で｡
Yeah, just send an invoice.
To Toshiro Hijikata.
あれ？ どっかで
見たことあるなｱｲﾂ｡
Oh?
He looks awfully familiar.
あれって… う～っ！
Isn't that--
N-Now that I think about it, I recall seeing him...
(土方)そっ そういや
いたような気がする！
よ よく考えたらいたわ
お前らのﾁｰﾑに外国人１人｡
That's right! There was a foreigner on your team!
あ～ あの名前なんだっけ？
Uh, what was his name again?
Taka-tin.
ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ｡
そう ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ！
Yeah! Taka-tin!
いたわ ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ！
Yeah, there was a Taka-tin!
Sorry about making false accusations.
妙な言いがかりつけて
悪かったな｡
山崎も
すっかり立派になっちゃって｡
Yamazaki's also grown so fine.
よし そうと決まったら
早く本戦いこう｡
Okay, with that all settled, let's move on to the finals.
あまり よそ見をせずに
本戦いこう！
No looking around. Let's just move on!
わかってんならいいんだよ｡
As long as you understand...
最初から
おとなしくそうしてれば…｡
You should have behaved to begin with.
大丈夫？ あれだったら
中まで案内するけど｡
Is this okay?
I can take you inside.
(近藤)大丈夫です｡
じゃあ 気をつけてね｡
This is fine.
Then be careful.
もう迷子になるんじゃないよ｡
Don't get lost again.
["From A Foreigner's Perspective, You're The Foreigner. From An Alien's Perspective, You're The Alien."]
寺門通 ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞ
決定戦場のﾋﾟｱﾆｽﾄ｡
And the pianist battle to decide Tsu Terakado's official fan club...
始まって早々
波乱が巻き起こっています｡
It's only just begun and we've already got a wild one on our hands!
予選ﾏﾗｿﾝ勝負
ｹｶﾞ人 脱落者 棄権者が相次ぎ➡
With all the injuries, desertions,
and dropouts, out of the thousand teams in the marathon prelims,
およそ1,000ﾁｰﾑ中
ｺﾞｰﾙまで たどりついたのは➡
only two teams, the Tsu Terakado Fan Club and the Tsusengumi,
寺門通親衛隊と通選組
たったの２ﾁｰﾑ｡
made it to the finish line!
しかも 迷子のところを 警察に
保護されて ﾊﾟﾄｶｰでｺﾞｰﾙという➡
On top of that, both teams had participants who got lost before being taken in
by the police and delivered here, a stretch of the rules...
微妙な判定の選手も
出ているんですが…｡
(神楽)どこが微妙ｱﾙか！
How is that a stretch?!
Did you ever say that we couldn't get in a car?!
ﾙｰﾙ説明のときに お前 ひと言でも
車に乗ったらﾀﾞﾒって言ったｱﾙか｡
いや 確かに言わなかったけど➡
No, I didn't say anything about that,
言わなくても 普通
あの わかるんじゃないですか｡
but normally, I wouldn't need to tell people this, right?
(近藤)いや わかるわけねえだろ！
ｵﾚたちが どれだけﾊﾞｶか➡
How could we possibly know?!
Do you have any idea how stupid we are?!
わかってんのか？
あんまなめてんじゃねえぞ！
Don't underestimate us!
そうｱﾙ ﾊﾞｶにするもの
いい加減にしろよ！
That's right! Don't play us for fools!
えっと お通ちゃん
どうなんでしょう？
Uh, Otsu-chan, what do you think?
ﾏﾗｿﾝ勝負で
車を使うっていうのは➡
Using a car in a marathon is most definitely...
これは どう考えても…｡
これは 私への愛を見せてくれる
大会なんですよね｡
The purpose of this contest is to show their love for me, right?
ﾏﾗｿﾝ勝負で車を使ってまで
私に会いに来てくれるなんて➡
To go as far as to use a car in a marathon to come see me...
愛以外の何ものでもないと
私は思います｡
I believe that it can only be love!
(観客たち)えぇ～!?
えっと 今になって
とんでもない事実が発覚しました｡
Uh, we've just been treated to an amazing revelation.
予選のﾏﾗｿﾝ勝負 車を使っても
ありだったようです｡
You were allowed to use a car in the marathon prelims.
おい ﾏｼﾞかよ！何だったんだ？
今までのｵﾚたちの努力は｡
Hey! Are you serious?!
What was all our effort for?!
最初から言えよ！
どうしてくれんだ！
You should have told us in the beginning!
How are you going to make up for this?!
え～ 文句が出るのも
わかりますが➡
Well, I can understand the complaints,
これは お通ちゃんのｵﾌｨｼｬﾙﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞ
決定戦場のﾋﾟｱﾆｽﾄです｡
but this is the pianist battle to decide Tsu Terakado's official fan club!
お通ちゃんの意見は絶対です｡
Otsu-chan's opinion is absolute.
よって 本戦に臨むのは
この２ﾁｰﾑ｡
So these two teams, the Tsu Terakado Fan Club and the Tsusengumi, will advance to the finals.
寺門通親衛隊と通選組｡
この２ﾁｰﾑに お通ちゃんの
ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞの座をかけて➡
These two teams will battle for the honor of becoming Otsu-chan's official fan club.
戦ってもらいます｡
《まずい… まずいぞ｡
This is bad. Very bad...
まさか こんな
直接対決の構図になるとは｡
I didn't expect to end up in a direct confrontation with them.
親衛隊さえ蹴落とせば
あとは すべて ｵﾚの手駒｡
Only my pawns would have remained once I eliminated their fan club.
どうにでもなると踏んで➡
I figured I could just wing it and picked up random members.
こっちは適当なﾒﾝﾊﾞｰしか
用意してねえぞ》
おたく誰？
Who are you?
《どうする… どうする？》
What do I do? What do I do?!
(近藤)顔色が悪いぞ ﾄｼ
大丈夫か？
You look pale, Toshi.
You okay?
心配するな
ここにいるのは➡
Don't worry.
The people here
お前が妖刀に とり憑かれたことを
知る 数少ないﾒﾝﾊﾞｰ｡
are among the few who know that you've been possessed by that demonic sword.
お前を妖刀から解放するために
ｵﾚが募った真の仲間たちだ｡
True comrades gathered to free you from that fiendish blade!
あんな金だけが目的の連中に
遅れはとらん｡
We won't lose to that money-hungry bunch.
(近藤)なあ 総悟｡
すいやせん｡
Right, Sogo?
Excuse me, how big is the reward?
賞金って いくらなんですかね？
(近藤)なあ 山崎｡
すみません｡
Right, Yamazaki?
Excuse me, how expensive is a hair transplant?
植毛って
いくらくらいかかるんですか？
(近藤)ﾀﾞｰﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
まったくｼｬｲなﾔﾂらよ｡
They're such a shy bunch!
あっ ところでﾄｼ ｵﾚ ３時から
とっつぁんとｺﾞﾙﾌなんだけど➡
By the way, Toshi,
I've gotta go play golf with the old man at three.
これ 何時くらいに
終わるのかな？
What time does this end?
これから行われる３本勝負にて
より多くの勝利をおさめたﾁｰﾑに➡
We will now hold three contests,
and the team which wins more contests shall win the right to be the official fan club!
ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞの座が与えられます｡
予選にて示してもらったのは体力｡
The prelims were a test of stamina!
続いて 試させてもらうのは➡
Next, we will test...
知力です｡
your brains!
大好きなお通ちゃんのことなら
何でも知っていて当然のはず｡
You should know everything there is to know about your beloved Otsu-chan!
これから お通ちゃんに関する
ｸｲｽﾞを出題させてもらいます｡
We will now have a quiz on matters related to Otsu-chan!
そして 皆様の解答席は➡
And you will be giving your answers from this slide!
こちらの滑り台です｡
問題に正解すると➡
When you get a question right, the opposing team's slide will tilt at a sharper angle!
相手ﾁｰﾑの滑り台の傾斜が
きつくなっていきます｡
最終的に 相手ﾁｰﾑのﾒﾝﾊﾞｰ
すべてを下に落とせば➡
Victory will go to which ever team makes the other team's members fall off!
勝利となります｡
しかし もし 問題を間違えれば
ﾍﾟﾅﾙﾃｨｰとして➡
However, if you get a question wrong, your own slide will tilt, so be careful!
自分の滑り台が上がりますので
気をつけてください｡
それでは
準備 よろしいでしょうか？
Is everybody ready then?
本戦１戦目｡
The first contest of the finals!
ｸｲｽﾞ対決 開始！
Commence the quiz showdown!
新八!!
Shinpachi!
What are you doing?!
何やってんだ！
The fan club has lost a critical member at the very beginning?!
これは 親衛隊 のっけから
貴重な戦力を失ってしまった！
いったい どうしたんでしょうか？
What happened?!
Did his hand slip?
手でも滑らせて
しまったんでしょうか？
Shinpachi Shimura has an expression filled with regret!
志村氏 無念の表情です！
ﾂｯｺめ!!
Charge!
なに滞りなく 話 進んでんの!?
なに勝手に本戦 始めてんの!?
Why are you moving on like nothing's wrong?!
Why are you starting the finals without me?!
あら？ ここにも志村氏が？
あら？ じゃねえだろ！
Oh? Shimura is also over here?!
Oh, my ass!
今 ようやく ﾏﾗｿﾝ終えて
到着したとこなんだよ！
I just finished the marathon and made it here!
仲間にｴｻにされて 必死に
ここまで辿り着いたんだよ!!
I had to struggle to make it here after being used as a decoy by my comrades!
(近藤)あれ？ まだ
着いてなかったんだ 新八君｡
Oh? You weren't here yet, Shinpachi-kun?
(神楽)気づかなかったｱﾙ｡
I didn't even notice.
We were moving along like nothing was wrong at all.
まったく何の支障もなく
話 進んでたもんな｡
あっ… 何？ ちょっと…｡
What?
Wait...
ﾏｼﾞで 誰も ﾎﾞｸがいないことに
気づいてなかったの？
Seriously? Nobody noticed that I was missing?
ちょっと やめてくれませんか？
その真顔｡
Could you drop the serious looks?
全員 八つ裂きにしますよ｡
I'll tear you all apart.
まあ とにかく
ここまで遅れたﾍﾟﾅﾙﾃｨｰで➡
Well, in any case,
your tardiness means that you're disqualified from the quiz showdown.
あなたは このｸｲｽﾞ勝負
失格ということで｡
ちょっと待ってくださいよ！
ﾁｰﾑﾒﾝﾊﾞｰが上位に入れば➡
Hold it right there!
You people were the ones who said it was okay
他は いくら遅れてもいいって
言ってたのは ｱﾝﾀらでしょ!?
for the other members to take their time,
as long as one member on the team placed!
You people were the ones who forgot about me!
勝手に ﾎﾞｸの存在 忘れてたのは
ｱﾝﾀらでしょ？
新八… 心配するな｡
Shinpachi, don't worry!
We don't need you to beat these guys down!
お前がいなくても こんなﾔﾂらには
ｵﾚたちは負けねえよ｡
それ 新八じゃねえって
いってるだろ！
That's not Shinpachi!
Those aren't even Shinpachi's glasses!
新八のﾒｶﾞﾈですらねえし!!
《しめた… ﾔﾂがいないのであれば
勝負は こっちのものだ》
Score.
If he's out of the picture, we've won.
勝手に頭の中 見て
すみませんけど➡
I apologize for reading your mind,
想像くらい
ちゃんとしませんか？
but could you at least use a better image to represent me?!
And why are they cracked?!
しかも なんで割れてんの!?
どういう意味？ それ!?
What's that supposed to mean?!
それでは 気を取り直して第１問｡
なに？ ﾎﾝﾄに出れないの？
Then we'll pick up where we left off with the first question!
What?! I really don't get to participate?!
ﾎﾝﾄに ﾎﾞｸ 参加できないの？
I don't get to join in?!
What is the name of the movie Otsu-chan saw when she was four and loves to death?
あ～っ！ 超簡単だよ!!
これ 教えちゃﾀﾞﾒなんですか？
This is super easy!
Am I not allowed to say it?!
ﾁｰﾑのみんなに伝えちゃ
ﾀﾞﾒなんですか？
Am I not allowed to tell my team members?!
(ﾎﾞﾀﾝを押す音)
Hijikata from the Tsusengumi!
通選組 土方氏！
『ﾛｰﾏの災日』｡
Roman Horrorday.
[Note: Parody of the movie Roman Holiday.]
《ぐっ… 正解だ…｡
お通ちゃんが お父さんと➡
He's right...
The last movie Otsu-chan went to see with her father...
一緒に見にいった最後の映画
『ﾛｰﾏの災日』｡
Roman Horrorday!
土方さん 妖刀から
解放されるためとはいえ➡
Hijikata-san...
Even if it's to free himself from the demonic sword,
やはり お通ちゃんのこと
勉強してきてる｡
he's done his research about Otsu-chan.
まずい…｡
This is bad...
Gin-san and the others don't stand a chance without me!
ﾎﾞｸがいなきゃ 銀さんたちじゃ
太刀打ちできない！》
《悪いが 予習は
しっかり済ませてあるぜ｡
Sorry, but I came prepared.
この勝負 もらった！》
This contest is mine!
(不正解ﾌﾞｻﾞｰ)
Too bad! Incorrect!
残念！ 不正解です｡
《新八/土方:なに!?》
What?!
惜しかったですね｡ 正解は→
So close.
The correct answer is Roman Horrorday, Gangster High School Rock and Roll!
え～っ!?
Too bad!
残念！ 土方氏 うっかり語尾に➡
Hijikata forgot to add an Otsu suffix at the end!
お通語をつけるのを
忘れてしまいました｡
Hold on! Forgot to...?
ちょっと待て！
うっかりって そんなﾙｰﾙ…｡
That wasn't a rule...
[ﾏｲｸ]
そ
れ
で
は
土
方
氏
ﾍﾟ
ﾅ
ﾙ
ﾃ
ｨ
で
一
段
階
滑
り
台
が
上
り
ま
す
｡
So as a penalty, Hijikata's slide will tilt one notch higher!
いや ちょっと 待てって！
No, wait, hold on!
(土方)どこが一段階～!?
How was that one notch...?!
あ～っと 土方氏
さっそく脱落してしまいました｡
Oh, Hijikata has already been eliminated!
あ あの すみません 一段階って
あんなに上がるんですか？
U-Uh, excuse me.
Was that really just one notch?
ほとんど90度になってんっすけど｡
That's like a 90 degree angle.
Otsu-chan has control over the slides.
[ﾏｲｸ]滑り台の角度のさじ加減は
お通ちゃんが握っています｡
The angle changes according to how Otsu-chan feels.
[ﾏｲｸ]お通ちゃんの気持次第で
角度は変わります｡
Otsu-chan is the law here!
[ﾏｲｸ]ここでは お通ちゃんがﾙｰﾙです｡
どんだけｱﾊﾞｳﾄなんだよ！
ｵﾚ そんなに悪いことした？
How capricious are you?!
Did I do something bad to you?!
お通語使わないのが
そんなに気にくわなかった？
Was it so wrong of me not to use an Otsu suffix?!
[ﾏｲｸ]両ﾁｰﾑ 早くもｷｬﾌﾟﾃﾝを
失ってしまいました｡
Both teams have already lost their captains!
[ﾏｲｸ]これは 勝負の行方が
俄然 読めなくなってきました！
This match is completely up for grabs!
What do we do?
《どうすんだ？ お通ちゃんのこと
知ってるﾔﾂなんて➡
Nobody in there knows a thing about Otsu-chan!
あんなかには 誰もいねえぞ!?》
《恐らく 向こうも➡
I'm sure that the other side also recruited members at random.
適当にかき集めた仲間で
あることは間違いない｡
向こうも こっちも 同じ状況｡
ならば…｡
We're both in the same situation.
In that case, the best strategy would be to not answer.
ここは 何も答えないのが得策だ》
It'd be better to wait for the other team to screw up instead of fumbling for an answer.
《下手に動くより
相手が自爆するのを待つんだ》
["As Immovable as a Mountain."]
Then, here's the second question.
[ﾏｲｸ]それでは第２問｡
Don't answer!
《新八/土方:答えるな
なにも答えるな!!》
Don't say anything!
《何も知らねえくせに 早押し!?
誰だ いったい誰だ!?》
Pressing the buzzer so early when you don't know anything?!
Who was that?!
Who the hell did that?!
[ﾏｲｸ]親衛隊 ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ氏
答えをどうぞ｡
Taka-tin from the Fan Club!
Please give us your answer!
《な なんでお前が押してんだ!?
Wh-Why did you press it?!
お前は
いちばんあり得ねえだろう！
You have the least chance!
You definitely have no clue!
お前は 絶対 何も知らねえだろう
つ～か 何 あれ？》
And what is that?!
おう ちょっと待ってください｡
Please wait a moment.
Why did you press the buzzer so early when you can barely speak?!
《言葉もろくに話せないのに
なに早押しなんかしてんの!?
And who the hell is that?!
つ～か 誰あれ？
むっ いや 待て｡
No, wait.
これだけ不利な要素を
抱えていながら➡
It's too odd for him to press the buzzer when so many factors are against him.
早押しするだなんて
逆におかしい｡
And the way he looks so confident...
妙に自信のある表情といい…｡
Maybe we have a chance here...
もしかして 何か
勝算があるのかもしれ…》
すみません｡
Sorry. Can I go take a piss? Kadomatsu mark the way to hell.
[Note: Refers to rare proverb meaning "When you see Kadomatsu (gate pines) in new years, it means you're a year older.]
《ただの小便かい!!
He just wants to take a piss?!
わざわざ ﾎﾞﾀﾝ押して
なに宣言してんだ？
You hit the buzzer so you could say that?!
And how come your Otsu suffix sounded perfectly fluent when the rest was shaky?!
っつうか かたことなのに
なんで➡
お通語のとこだけ
日本語ﾍﾟﾗﾍﾟﾗなんだよ！
日本人だって知らないような
ことわざ出てきたよ！
That was a phrase most Japanese people don't even know!
やられた 完全に１問損し…》
We've been done in!
Now we're one question in the hole...
(正解ﾁｬｲﾑ)
正解！
Correct!
The question was, "What was the first thing Otsu-chan said
to the audience as a nervous wreck during her first concert?"
The answer is,
Can I go take a piss?
[ﾏｲｸ]ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ氏 問題も聞かずに
みごと正解！
Taka-tin gave the correct answer without hearing the question!
《あ 当たった～!!
H-He got it right!
Why?!
なんでだ～
どんなﾐﾗｸﾙ起こしてんだ!?》
What kind of miracle was that?!
Amazing!
すごいｱﾙ よくわかったｱﾙな
ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ！
How did you know, Taka-tin?
ﾍｲ ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ ﾍｲ！
ﾉ ﾉｰ…｡
Hey, Taka-tin! Hey!
N-No...
[ﾏｲｸ]通選組 ﾁｰﾑ全員
一段上げさせてもらいます｡
The entire Tsusengumi team will have their slides raised a notch.
え？
あの お通ちゃん
なんか気のせいか➡
Uh...
Otsu-chan?
Is it my imagination or is my slide the only one at an extremely steep angle?
ｵﾚだけ 角度が
きつい気がするんだけど｡
これって どういうことなのかな？
What might this mean?
それでは ３問目いきます｡
Then, we'll move onto the third question.
Hey! You're ignoring me?!
(近藤)あれ 無視 無視なの？
You're gonna ignore me?!
Please have a look at this clip!
まずは この映像をご覧ください｡
(ﾎﾞﾀﾝを押す音)
What?! They haven't even played anything!
《なんだ!?
まだ 何の絵も流れて…》
[ﾏｲｸ]またも 親衛隊のﾀｶﾃｨﾝ氏だ！
It's Taka-tin from the Fan Club again!
《だから なんで お前だ!! 小便
行きたかったんじゃないのかよ！
Why you?!
Didn't you want to go take a piss?!
つ～か ＶＴＲも見ないで
何答える気だ!?》
And what kind of answer are you going to give without watching the clip?!
なんだっけ…｡
ｸｯ！ なんだ… まさか!?
What was it again...?
What?
Could it be...
[Note: Kiyohara-kun is a baseball player.]
Do the bathrooms here have washlets? Hit the ball Kiyohara-kun.
今度は大きいほうかい～!!
This time it's number two?!
ｼｯﾄ！
Shit!
正解！
(正解ﾁｬｲﾑ)
Correct!
えぇ～!?
The question was, "What was the first item Otsu-chan bought at this store?"
The answer was a washlet!
そんなｱｲﾄﾞﾙのいらねえﾌﾟﾗｲﾍﾞｰﾄ
公開すんな～!!
Don't reveal private information about an idol that nobody wants to know!
ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ氏 みごと連続正解です！
Taka-tin has managed to answer consecutive questions correctly!
ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ やったね！
ﾍｲ！ ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ ﾍｲ！
Taka-tin, way to go!
Hey, Taka-tin! Hey!
それでは通選組！
また一段あげさせてもらいます！
So, the Tsusengumi will be raised another notch!
それでは
４問目いってみましょう！
And we'll move onto the fourth question!
(近藤)いや… だからなんで!?
No, seriously, why?!
Oh, it's Taka-tin again!
お～っと！ またまたﾀｶﾃｨﾝ氏！
This time, he hit the buzzer without hearing a single word!
今度は 問題をひと言すら聞かずに
ﾎﾞﾀﾝを押した！
What?!
えぇ～!?
《ﾊﾞｶが！
Fool.
奇跡が三度も続くわけがない！
今度こそ水に沈むがいい！》
A miracle can't happen three times in a row.
You'll be in the water for sure!
《いや…｡
今度こそ確信をもって言える！
No, I can be certain this time.
あの人は ただ者じゃない！
That person isn't ordinary!
そう｡ あの人はきっと
ﾎﾞｸらを救うために➡
Yes, he must be the ultimate savior brought by Gin-san to help us!
銀さんが連れてきた
最強の助っ人なんだ！
He'll make this work somehow...
あの人なら なんとかしてくれる！
He'll give us another miracle!
あの人なら… もう一度
奇跡を起こしてくれる!!》
さぁ ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ氏！ 答えを！
Well, Taka-tin. Give us your answer!
Go, Taka-tin!!
いっけ～！ ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ!!
Sorry, could I change my underwear? Katochan, Pe.
[Note: "Katochan, Pe." is a popular phrase used by the comedian "Cha Kato"]
すみません｡
あっちがｲｯたぁ～!!
He's actually done it!
What?!
《えぇ～!?
So he just wanted to take a shit?!
やっぱ普通にｳﾝｺしたかった
だけだったんかい!!
He's done it now!
やっちゃったよ～｡
さっき行ってれば➡
He might have made it in time if he'd said something earlier!
間に合ったかもしれないのに！
And his Otsu suffix sounds a little strained!
お通語も心なしか
ﾔｹｸｿに聞こえる!!
あぁ…｡
もう お尻浮かしてんじゃん！
Yeah, he's propping his ass up...
Just let him go already!
もう行かせてあげて！
一気に引き上げて➡
Just raise it all the way and finish him off!
ﾄﾄﾞﾒをさしてあげて！
彼は よくやってくれたよ！
He's done well!
思う存分 ﾊﾟﾝﾂを取り替えてくれば
いいよ！》
You can change your underwear all you want!
正解!!
《２人:えぇ～!?》
Correct!
The question was, "What did Otsu-chan say when a friend caught her picking her nose?"
The answer is, Katochan, Pe!
お通語のほうかい!!
The Otsu suffix was right?!
And what kind of questions are these for a quiz about a popular idol?!
《つうか人気ｱｲﾄﾞﾙのｸｲｽﾞに➡
さっきから
なんつう問題出してんの!?》
ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ氏 なんと
奇跡の早押し連続３問正解！
Taka-tin has miraculously answered three questions correctly after buzzing in early!
しかも語尾につけるべき
お通語を➡
And he's even revealed a technique where the Otsu suffix becomes a prefix!
逆に頭につけるという
離れ技まで披露してくれました！
いや違うから！
その人ただもらして➡
No, you've got it wrong!
He's just a foreigner who's crapped his pants and wants to change his underwear!
ﾊﾟﾝﾂ取り替えたいだけの
外国人さんだから!!
Just let him go already!
もう行かせてあげて！
早くしないと➡
If you don't hurry up, it'll be all over his ass, so let him go!
お尻かぶれてくるから
行かせてあげて～!!
Taka-tin!
ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ！
ﾍｲ！ ﾀｶﾃｨﾝ ﾍｲ！
Hey, Taka-tin! Hey!
｢ﾍｲ｣ いいから！
｢ﾍｲ｣ もういいから！
Forget the "hey"!
Enough with the "hey" already!
Just let him use the water to wash down!
もういっそ
そこの水で洗わせてあげて!!
《でも ここまで来れば
勝利は目前！
But we're on the verge of winning...
Taka-tin soiled his pants to earn the blessing of the goddess of victory!
ﾀｶﾃｨﾝがﾊﾟﾝﾂを汚してまで
引き寄せてくれた勝利の女神！
ﾎﾞｸたちの力で
振り向かせましょう！》
We'll do whatever we can to keep her on our side!
Uh, Otsu-chan...
あの… お通さん？
Could it be that by some chance...
あの… ひょっとして…｡
ｵﾚのこと… 嫌い？
You hate me...?
正解!!
(歓声)
Correct!
The answer was, "I physically can't stand him."
The Tsusengumi has rebounded from the verge of defeat to win!
通選組 敗北寸前のところで➡
大逆転!!
三本勝負一本目➡
The first contest, the quiz showdown, goes to the Tsusengumi!
ｸｲｽﾞ勝負は➡
通選組の勝利!!
[To Be Continued]
[Preview]
The finals consist of three contests!
The second contest is a glamour showdown!
Glamour?!
How do you have a glamour showdown?!
How do you decide who wins?!
The next episode...
"Laputa's Still Good After Seeing It So Many Times."
Ready, and...
Barusu!
[Though getting here was difficult and exciting, the way back is surprisingly...not.]
[Next week is about maybe going to that place.]
[See you next time.]